<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Today I Learned - Agile Methodolody</title><link href="https://alexandremjacques.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://alexandremjacques.github.io/feeds/agile-methodolody.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://alexandremjacques.github.io/</id><updated>2020-04-10T19:19:00-03:00</updated><entry><title>Now, a Scrum.org PSD I and PSM I Certified</title><link href="https://alexandremjacques.github.io/scrum-org-psmi-certified.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-04-10T19:19:00-03:00</published><updated>2020-04-10T19:19:00-03:00</updated><author><name>Alexandre Jacques</name></author><id>tag:alexandremjacques.github.io,2020-04-10:/scrum-org-psmi-certified.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since before I started working at &lt;a href="https://agile.inc"&gt;Agile.Inc&lt;/a&gt;, around Dec/2019, I was aiming to...&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since before I started working at &lt;a href="https://agile.inc"&gt;Agile.Inc&lt;/a&gt;, around Dec/2019, I was aiming to get certified. Before
Agile.Inc I was a consultant for &lt;a href="https://accenture.com"&gt;Accenture&lt;/a&gt; for almost a full year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There I was consulting for a financial institution that was moving to a agile mindset. Not that they were near to
achieve something close to it but, as a requirement to me to be working there as a tech leader (whatever that means) I
was being requested to get PSM I certified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agile.Inc is a &lt;a href="https://scrum.org"&gt;Scrum.org&lt;/a&gt; official training partner and, not only that, all 4 Agile.Inc owners are offical
trainers for Scrum.org.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, being an employee, I get to participate on the official trainings free of charge. Official trainings also offers
free certification vouchers for participants (vouchers - plural - because you get 2 attempts to get certified).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I took trainings for the Professional Scrum Developer and for the Professional Scrum Master. Both trainings took
place at Agile.Inc offices and were awesome. They are actually great guides for the certifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agile methodologies are a thing here in Brazil. It's something that every company that is hiring is asking candidates to
be, at least, aware of. I may be wrong since I'm not an expert but it seems that agile is still a bit behind on US and
Europe in terms of adoption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not a huge fan of Scrum. I'm more of a XP Programming fellow. But, since both drink from the same fountain, it's
ok. I think that, as long as your business have an agile mindset, you're safe (not SAFe - winkle).&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Agile Methodolody"></category><category term="scrum"></category><category term="xp programming"></category><category term="certification"></category></entry></feed>